Mildred Gilman Wohlforth Papers, 1910-1994 (bulk 1927-1985 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Mildred Gilman Wohlforth Papers
1910-1994
1927-1985
C0842
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
12 linear feet 25 boxes
Wohlforth, Mildred Gilman, 1896-1994.
Mildred Gilman Wohlforth was an American journalist, newspaper reporter, and novelist. Her papers include over 600 letters from friends, family, and literary associates, along with autograph and typed manuscripts for several unpublished novels. Also present are selected papers of her husband, Robert Wohlforth, a journalist, business analyst, and author.
Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, a graduate of the University of Wisconsin, married James Gilman and moved to New York, where she became Heywood Broun's secretary. From 1928 to 1931 she was a reporter for the New York Journal. After divorcing Gilman she married Robert Wohlforth in 1930, and published Sob Sister (1931), a novel about a female tabloid reporter which was made into a movie. In the late 1930s Wohlforth went to Germany as a reporter for the International News Service to interview Adolf Hitler and Hermann Goring, and worked for the Washington Herald covering Eleanor Roosevelt and New Deal projects. Settling in Ridgefield, Conn., Wohlforth wrote articles, stories and novels, worked for the Planned Parenthood Federation of America, raised three sons, and published her memoirs in 1973.
The collection consists of papers of Wohlforth. Included in the papers are over 600 letters from friends, family, and literary associates such as Barbara Belford, Silas Bent, Hewood Broun, Robert Benchley, Kyle Crichton, Zona Gale, Julian S. Huxley, Richard and Hildegarde Lockridge, H. L. Mencken, Ezra Pound, and Robert Wohlforth. There are autograph and typed manuscripts for several unpublished novels in various revisions with such titles as Diary of Alice, I Sobbed for Mr. Hearst, and The Woman Angle, as well as the manuscript for The Reminiscences of Mildred Gilman (1973); typescripts for some stories and many articles on a wide range of topics with many relating to issues of marriage and sexuality, such as "Are You Frigid," "Fearless Frances," "I Covered the Crash," "Safe Sex," and "Sob Sister Tells All"; contracts; documents; dreams recorded by Wohlforth; newspaper clippings; and about 120 photographs of the Wohlforth family, Mildred Wohlforth on various reporting assignments, friends, writers, and several movie actors and actresses, including Deanna Durbin, Jane Withers, Tyrone Power, Shirley Temple, Paul Robeson, Hermann Goring, Dorothy Parker, Hewood Broun, and others. There are two videocassettes of an interview with the Wohlforths.
Also present are selected papers of Robert Wohlforth, a journalist, business analyst, secretary-treasurer at Farrar, Straus Giroux, and author of an exposé novel of West Point entitled Tin Soldiers (1934), articles, and short stories. Included are about 100 letters to him by Harold Bender, Kyle Crichton, Pare Lorentz, Lewis Mumford, James Salter, Louis Untermeyer, and others, 15 typescripts of articles or stories, including "I Married a Sob Sister," and "A Nickelodeon Childhood," reviews of Tin Soldiers, and newspaper clippings.
Collection is open for research use.
Gift of Eric E. Wohlforth.
Germany. Heer -- Officers -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Planned Parenthood Federation of America.; Actors -- United States -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Actresses -- United States -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Journalism -- United States -- 20th century.; Journalists -- New York (State) -- New York -- 20th century.; Novelists, American -- 20th century.; Reporters and reporting -- 20th century.; Women authors, American -- 20th century.; Women's dreams.; Articles.; Clippings.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Videocassettes.; American literature
- Series 1: Correspondence of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, 1910-1991; 4 boxes
  - A: misc. (10), 1927-1983; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood (9), 1925-1930; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B: misc. (20), 1929-1988; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beasley, Maurine (5), 1982-1983; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Belford, Barbara (5), 1981-1982; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Benchley, Robert (1), 1928; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bent, Silas (1), 1931; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bloch, Ernest (6), 1927-1946; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Broun, Heywood (5), 1927-1983; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bruccoli, Matthew J. (6), 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (1), 1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C: misc. (15), 1926-1975; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cameron, Rhoda (5), 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Caspary, Vera (1), undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clark, Charles Upson (2), 1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Collins, Jean E. (9), 1979-1981; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cousins, Norman Ellen (3), 1980; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Crichton, Kyle Samuel (76), 1931-1960; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (20), 1941-1952; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - D: misc. (9), 1925-1988; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Davis, H. D. (Dickie) (23), 1931-1939; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - E: misc. (2), 1938-1942; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Evans, George D., Mr. Mrs. (parents) (37), 1910-1940; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - F: misc. (5), 1927-1980; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fox Film Corp. Studio (Irene Rene Kuhn) (5), 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - G: misc. (3), 1938; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gale, Zona (1), 1927; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gilman, Gertrude David (2), 1938; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - H: misc. (10), 1928-1987; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hansl, Helen (7), 1938; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harcourt, Brace Co. (6), 1938-1963; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr., Mrs. (1), circa 1979; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Herrmann, Dorothy (3), 1983; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Homestead Realtors (1), undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hurst, Fannie (1), 1942; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Huston, John (by secretary) (1), 1981; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Huxley, Julian S. (3), 1942-1959; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - I: misc. (1), 1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - J. B. Lippincott Company (1), 1963; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Jastrow, Joseph (2), 1928; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Jonathan Cape Limited (2), 1931; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - K: misc. (5), 1928-1938; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Kerrigan, Joe (3), 1927-1928; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - L: misc. (8), 1925-1975; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Le Gallienne, Hesper (2), 1925; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lockridge, Richard Hildegarde Dolson (33), 1970-1991; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lowell, Amy (1), 1920; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - M: misc. (9), 1927-1988; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - MacShane, Frank (4), 1978; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Marzolf, Marion (21), 1975-1983; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meade, Marion (1), 1982; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mencken, H. L. (38), 1926-1933; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - N: misc. (5), 1938-1956; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Nachman, Gerold (2), 1980; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The New York Times (8), 1936-1979; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The New Yorker (3), 1938-1946; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Osborn, Paul (1), 1947; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - P: misc. (5), 1937-1982; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Parrott, Ursula (4), 1934; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc. (5), 1942-1958; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pound, Ezra (1) from Italy, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Princeton University Library (Richard M. Ludwig) (5), 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - R: misc. (13), 1927-1985; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Richter, Hans Felix (5), 1931-1945; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ridgefield, Connecticut (4), 1976-1985; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Robeson, Paul (1), 1926; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (3), 1929-1950; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - S: misc. (6), 1944-1988; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sanger, Margaret (photocopy) (1), 1953; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sartain, Gerry (2), 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Seldes, Helen (Mrs. Gilbert Seldes) (1), undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Seltzer, Adele Szold (2), 1933; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Soskin, William (5), 1936-1938; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Spingarn, J. E. (1), 1938; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - T: misc. (6), 1923-1938; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - U: misc. (2), 1938-1966; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - V: misc. (2), 1956-1987; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem (4 + 1 drawing), 1926-1931; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - W: misc. (7), 1937-1989; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wohlforth, Eric (3), 1941; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wohlforth, Jim (8), 1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wohlforth, Robert (50), circa 1938; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Wohlforth, Tim (2), 1949-1984; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Zanuck, [Darryl] (1), undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - unidentified (45), 1926-1974; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series 2: Writings of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 16 boxes
  - Subseries 2A: Books, undated; 10 boxes
    - Confessions of a Hearst Sob Sister, undated; 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Diary of Alice The Traveling Salesman's Daughter, undated; 3 folders (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - Everything Went Black, undated; 4 folders (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Growing Up in Grand Rapids, undated; 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - I Sobbed for Mr. Hearst, undated; 5 folders (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Miami Story, undated; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Murder, Mayhem, and Good Clean Sex, undated; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
    - My Heart Bled, undated; 4 folders (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - The Old Man, undated; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Quiet Year, undated; 6 folders (Box 10, Folder 2-7)
    - The Quiet Year, undated; 4 folders (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
    - The Reminiscences of Mildred Gilman, undated; 2 folders (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Thirteen, undated; 3 folders (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
    - The Time is Now, undated; 4 folders (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Woman, undated; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - The Woman Angle, undated; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Pages, undated; 3 folders (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
    - Autobiographical Notes, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Autobiographical Writings, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2B: Articles Stories, undated; 6 boxes
    - 13 in 13', undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Abortion vs Birth Control in Japan, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - The Accidental Life of Mildred Evans Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Agnes Chase: My Most Unforgettalbe Character, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Animals Like Me, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Are You Frigid?, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - As Much As I Dare, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Aunt Angie, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Babies Are Indestructable, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Babies: Quantity or Quality?, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Babies Should Be Planned, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Back From Nature, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - The Best Methods, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - The Biggest and the Best, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Biological Method, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Birth Control, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Birth Control- Hush-hush Subject, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Box Office Technique, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - A Boy Named Jeff, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Brave Little Linda, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Characters in Sit-Up Special, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - City Desk, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Come Rain, Come Snow, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Cousin Rob, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Cowed, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Deadline, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Divide By Two, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Do We Welcome Babies?, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - A Doctor Talks to Wives, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - A Doctor's Advice to Brides, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Don't Play With Mexicans, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Don't Try to Be Funny in Connecticut, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Down With Geriatrics!, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Drusilla Faces Life, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Duebill Davis, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt: First Lady of the World, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Expecting Again, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Extended vs. Neuclear, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Faces, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Fearless Frances, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Five Dollar Room, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - For Immediate Release, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Frank Answers to Bride's Questions, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Frigidity, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Frugality Almost Killed Me, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Garbo's Aunt Angie, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Geronimo, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Golden Mae, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Grandma Lizzie, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Grandma Still Goes Sailing, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - The Help Meet, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Henry's Women, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - His Overcoat Was Too Long, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - House Tour, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Housing and Birth Control, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - How Can I Learn to Love My Mother-in-Law?, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - How Much Do We Know About Women?, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - I Covered the Crash, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Ice Storm in Ridgefield, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - I'm Glad I Went Along, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Is Marriage a Failure?, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - It Wasn't All Our Fault, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Italy in Strike Time, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Japan's Birth-Rate War, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Japan Wants Birth Control, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Junk Can Be Art, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Lady With Voodoo Dancers, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Letter of Inquiry, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - A Lifetime Responsibility to the Challenge of Health, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Little Case History, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Long vs Short Skirts, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - The Love Cure, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Love My Neighbor, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Main Road to Chicago, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Make-Believe Hero, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Make it a Marriage, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Making it Safer to Be Born, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Margeret Sanger Back from India, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Margert Sanger, Birth Control, and World Peace, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Married to Genius, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Marry That Man, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mary Agnes Chase, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Million Dollar Sally, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Miss Louise, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - And Mom Hung Up!, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Moody's Guilty, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Murder Walks the Lonely Streets of Queens... The Mass Killer is at Large Again, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - My Father Enjoys Being Eighty, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - My Friend's Ashes, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - My Mother Was Usually Right, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - My Young Man, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Neuclear or Extended?, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - New Hope for the Newborn, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - A New Life, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - The No Baby Pill, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - No One Ever Follows My Good Advice- Why?, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Not Guilty!, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - The Not So Lonely Years, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Number Thiry-Five, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - The Oaf From Oklahoma, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - The Old Maid's Story, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - The Oldest Living Whatever, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - On the Town, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Once is Enough, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - One Day With Althea, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Oslo, Flatbush, and Points West, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Parachute Jump, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Perfection is Not Quite Possible, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Planned Parenthood, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Planned Parenthood and Sex Education, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Progress in India's Vast Birth Control Experiment, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Publicity Permanent, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Quonset Fifth Avenue, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Ready-Made Family, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Religious Support for Family Planning Shown in New Folder, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Return With Me, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - River Holding, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - The Roller Coaster, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Safe Sex, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Sex-- Facts Not Fantasies, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Sex Questions Engaged Couples Ask, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Sex Questions of High School Girls, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Shake-Down Sheet, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - The Sins of the Fathers, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Sob Sister Tells All, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - South of the Brown Derby, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Speech, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Spilled Salt, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Stand on the Dotted Line, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Straight From Eve, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Summer Madness, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Surprise For Sally, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Terra Firma For Me, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Thanks to Andy, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - They Don't Know All the Answers, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Thirty Dress Shirts, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - This Transitory Life, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - This Way to the Battlefield, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Three Thousand Feet Above New York City, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Tightwad, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - A Tip For Hearst, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Tomorrow is Here, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Twas Brillig and the Slithy Toves, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - 'Twas the Night Before Christmas, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Twenty-Five Cent Valentine, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Voice of Mother Spurs a Daughter, at 90, to Make Use of Every Moment, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - We Took the High Road, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - We're Not Birds or Flowers, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - What the Modern Wife Should Know About Birth Control and Fertility, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - What You Could Once Buy For a Nickel, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - When Babies Aren't Wanted, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - When Your Mate is Also Your First Mate, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Who's Afraid?, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Why Does My Husband Have Sexual Difficulties?, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Why They Can't Wait to Wed, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - The Wicked Rich, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - A Wife is Born, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Winter Widow, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Without Fear, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Woman's Angle on Wall Street, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Women's Secret Fear, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - A Word to Troubled Wives, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - The World of Marianne, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Wrong Number!, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - You're Immature-- So What?, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified, undated; 3 folders (Box 20, Folder 21-23)
- Series 3: Miscellaneous Papers, 1923-1956; 6 folders
  - Subseries 3A: Contracts, 1925-1956; 1 folder
    - Contracts, 1925-1956; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3B: Correspondence of Others, 1923-1949; 1 folder
    - Gilman, James from his father Scholastic Magazine (2), 1948-1949; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Lewis, Sinclair to Heywood Broun (1), 1926; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Markham, Edwin to Florence Hamilton (1), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Lofting, Hugh to James Gilman (2), 1923; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Powers, Mary to Mrs. Evans (1), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Wells, Carolyn to Heywood Broun (1), 1926; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3C: Documents Memorabilia, undated; 1 folder
    - Documents Memorabilia, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3D: Drawings of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder
    - Drawings of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3E: Dreams of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder
    - Dreams of Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3F: Videocassettes (2): Wohlforth interview, undated; 1 folder
    - Videocassettes (2): Wohlforth interview, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Series 4: Printed Matter, 1981-1989; more than 6 folders
  - Clippings: “In Memorium, Articles Interviews, ”, 1981-1989; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: “A Life in Local Newspaper Clippings”, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: About Mildred Gilman Wohlforth, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 3)